statsheet.com 2019-03-01

# Privacy Policy | Automated Insights

PRIVACY POLICY Automated Insights, Inc. (“Company”, “we” or “us”) maintains the Websites automatedinsights.com, app.automatedinsights.com, and wordsmith.automatedinsights.com (collectively, the “Website”).

Registered users can use the Website to remotely access and use our proprietary software application (“Wordsmith”). Users provide their own structured data and text (the “User Content”), which Wordsmith transforms into narrative content (the “Articles”). For an additional fee, we also provide training and consulting services to help You better use Wordsmith. All of the foregoing are cumulatively referred as our “Services”.

All information that we collect on the Website, including any information that You provide to create Articles, is subject to this privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”).

By using the Website, or by clicking to accept or agree to the Terms of Use when this option is made available to You, You accept and agree to be bound and abide by this Privacy Policy.

If You do not want to agree to this Privacy Policy, You must not provide us with any personal information.

This Privacy Policy covers the Company’s treatment of personal information that the Company gathers when You use the Website or the Services, including personal information provided during registration or included in User Content.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to third parties that the Company does not own or control. If You have any questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy or its enforcement, please contact us at privacy@automatedinsights.com.

1\. NOTICE – INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND USE.

A. We collect and store information that registered users (“Customers” or “You”) submit to us, such as their names and e-mail addresses, to allow us to identify Customers, provide the Services and notify Customers of changes or updates to the Services. When Customers provide us with their e-mail addresses, they automatically opt-in to receive e-mails from us (including marketing e-mails). If a Customer would like to opt-out of these marketing e-mails, he, she or it can change its settings through its account page. We also collect and store the Customer’s name and phone number if a Customer elects to provide such information, which we use to assist us in providing the Services. We also collect other information from Customers, such as the Customer’s IP address and browser type. We use the IP addresses of Customers to assist in login and other uses related to Customers’ use of the Services. Customers’ sessions on the Website are tracked for systems administration purposes and to track user trends. We may link IP address and other information to a Customer’s account.

B. You may include your personal information in User Content. With our express prior consent, You may include the personal information of third parties in User Content. We use this information for internal research purposes, to operate, manage and improve our Services offerings, and to create Articles.

C. As You navigate through and interact with our Website, we may automatically collect certain traffic data and usage information to help us manage our content and improve your use of the Website. This may include information about your equipment, your IP address and your browsing actions and patterns when You visit our Website, including the referring and exit pages.

D. Like many other websites, we use a standard technology called “cookies.” Cookies are small pieces of information stored on your hard drive. They can help make the Internet experience quicker and more convenient. Cookies allow Customers to login without entering their user ID and password each time they use the Service. Cookies also allow us to improve the Service. Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing You to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. If you disable cookies, You will not be able to use the Service.

Cookie| Type| Duration| Description  
---|---|---|---  
__cfduid| persistent| 1 year| Used by the content network, Cloudflare, to identify trusted web traffic.  
_calendly_session| persistent| 3 weeks| Stores a session_id for Calendly to operate.  
_ga| persistent| 2 year| Used by Google Analytics to distinguish users.  
_gat| session| 1 minute| Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate.  
_gat_admin| persistent| 1 minute| Used by Google analytics to throttle request rate.  
_gat_UA-47052155-1| persistent| 1 minute| Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate.  
_gcl_au| persistent| 3 months| Used by Google AdSense for experimenting with advertisement efficiency across websites using their services.  
_gid| persistent| 1 day| Used by Google Analytics to distinguish users over short periods of time.  
_mkto_trk| persistent| 2 years| A cookie used by Marketo's Munchkin scripts for tracking user behavior on the website and creating leads on the Marketo platform.  
bcookie| persistent| 2 years| Browser ID cookie set by LinkedIn.  
BIGipServersjnweb-nginx-app_https| persistent| | Cookies used by Marketo are used to track engagement and conversion and to make content more engaging to users.  
BizoID| persistent| 1 month| LinkedIn Ad analytics  
bscookie| persistent| 2 years| Secure browser ID cookie set by LinkedIn.  
cookielawinfo-checkbox-analytics| persistent| 1 year| Served by Automated Insights to determine whether the user has accepted the "analytics" cookie category. Necessary for the GDPR functionality.  
cookielawinfo-checkbox-functionality| persistent| 1 year| Served by Automated Insights to determine whether the user has accepted the "functionality" cookie category. Necessary for the GDPR functionality.  
cookielawinfo-checkbox-marketing| persistent| 1 year| Served by Automated Insights to determine whether the user has accepted the "marketing" cookie category. Necessary for the GDPR functionality.  
GPS| persistent| 30 minutes| Registers a unique ID on mobile devices to enable tracking based on geographical GPS location.  
HBsession| persistent| | Used by Hirebridge to maintain authentication for jobseekers and applicants on the website  
IDE| persistent| 2 years| Used by Google DoubleClick to register and report the website user's actions after viewing or clicking one of the advertiser's ads with the purpose of measuring the efficacy of an ad and to present targeted ads to the user.  
lang| persistent| | Remembers the user's selected language version of a website for LinkedIn.  
lidc| persistent| 1 day| Used for routing by LinkedIn.  
test_cookie| persistent| 15 minutes| Used by Google to check if the user's browser supports cookies.  
UserMatchHistory| persistent| 1 month| LinkedIn Ad analytics  
viewed_cookie_policy| persistent| 1 hour| Served by Automated Insights to determine whether the cookie bar has been viewed by the user.  
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE| persistent| 5 months| A cookie that YouTube sets that measures your bandwidth to determine whether you get the new player interface or the old.  
YSC| persistent| | Registers a unique ID to keep statistics of what videos from YouTube the user has seen.  
  
2\. DATA INTEGRITY – HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION.

We generally use the information we collect to create a secure and personalized Service.

A. We gather IP Addresses for systems administration purposes, abuse prevention and to track user trends. We may also use your IP address to identify the general geographic area from which You are accessing our Website. We do not link IP addresses to any personally identifiable information.

B. We collect Customers’ user IDs and password information to enable them to log into and use the Service.

C. Customers are automatically opted-in to receive marketing e-mails from us when they register for the Service. Customers can opt-out of such e-mails by adjusting their account settings, provided that we may still send Customers e-mails relating to their accounts.

D. We collect Customers’ names and phone numbers, which allow us to contact them in account recovery and other scenarios.

E. We use this information for internal research purposes, to operate, manage and improve our Services offerings, and to create Articles.

F. We use traffic data and usage information to help us manage our content and improve your use of the Website.

3\. ONWARD TRANSFER – DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES.

A. Except as expressly provided otherwise herein, we will not sell, lease or exchange the personal information of our Customers to third parties without first obtaining their express consent, unless required by law or to protect their status as a Customer. To the extent we do disclose your personal information to a third party to protect your status as a Customer, we will notify You in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

B. We may aggregate and anonymize Customers’ traffic data with that from other Customers to provide benchmarking data and other functionality, but we will not disclose aggregated traffic data in a manner that reveals the identity of a Customer without the Customer’s express prior consent.

C. We employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information, including User Content, with them to provide products and services. Examples include billing, technical assistance, and customer service. We require our agents to contractually subscribe to the same level of privacy protection as detailed in this policy. Unless we inform You otherwise, our agents do not have any right to use the personal information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us.

D. The Company may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if the Company, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, user information would be one of the assets that is reviewed and transferred or acquired by a third party. Accordingly, You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of the Company may continue to use your personal information, including User Content, as set forth in this policy.

E. We also may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

F. In cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of EU or Swiss individuals received pursuant to the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Frameworks (see Section 11 below), the Company remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles of third-party agents that the Company engages to process the personal information or data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless the Company proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

4\. CHOICE.

A. We will not use or share your personal information other than as set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as You have explicitly authorized, without obtaining your consent.

B. If you do not want us to share your personal information with third parties as set forth in this Privacy Policy, you can opt-out by sending us an e-mail stating your request to privacy@automatedinsights.com.

C. If at any time we would like to disclose your personal information to a third party in a manner other than as set forth in this Privacy Policy, we will provide You with an affirmative or explicit (opt-in) choice.

D. We will not use nor disclose any sensitive information related to your health, racial or ethnic identity, political and religious opinions, trade union membership or sex life to any third party without your consent, subject to certain limited exceptions permitted by the Privacy Shield. Should we wish to make any such disclosure, we will notify you by e-mail and request that You opt-in to such disclosure by responding to the email with your consent.

E. Personal information will not be used to directly market the Service to potential Customers unless that possible use of the information has been disclosed to You and You have authorized us to permit such disclosure.

F. As noted above, Customers may choose not to receive marketing e-mails from us and can opt out of such e-mails through their account settings.

5\. ACCESS.

A. Customers have a right to access their personal information/data stored by the Company by sending us an e-mail at privacy@automatedinsights.com.

B. We will allow Customers to correct, amend or erase their personal information that we retain to the extent it is inaccurate, or where it has been processed in violation of the EU-US or Swiss-Us Privacy Shield Principles (see Section 11 below), except where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to the privacy of the Customer in question, or where the rights of others would be violated. If requested to erase personal information or data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. Should You elect to correct, amend or erase any personally identifiable information included in User Content, You are solely responsible for any resulting changes in the Articles.

C. Customers who discontinue use of the Service may choose to have their personal information deleted from the Service by contacting privacy@automatedinsights.com. 

6\. LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES.

The Website may contain links to third-party websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of third-party websites You choose to visit. If You provide any information directly to parties other than us, different rules may apply to the use or disclosure of that information. We encourage You to investigate and ask questions before disclosing your personal information to third parties.

7\. THIRD PARTY ADVERTISERS. We may choose to deploy advertising on the Website or in connection with any Services that are delivered to users through a third party’s advertising server. Information about users’ use of the Website or Services, such as the number of times a user has viewed an ad (but no personally identifiable information of the user), would be used in such a scenario to serve ads to users of the Website or the Services.

8\. PRIVACY PROTECTION FOR CHILDREN. In compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), we do not knowingly provide access to the Website or the Services to persons under the age of thirteen (13). If we learn that any user of the Services is under the age of thirteen (13), we will take appropriate steps to remove that user’s information from our records and we will restrict that individual from future access to the Services. Our Website or Services may be used by children in the European Union between the ages of 13 and 16 only with parental consent. If we learn we have collected or received Personal Information from or about a child in the European Union under the age of 16 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. In addition, if we have collected Personal Information from any child in the European Union to provide goods or services to that child for a fee, we will erase the Personal Information of that child upon request.

9\. SECURITY. We have implemented security measures to protect user information from loss, misuse and alteration. We use industry-standard practices such as encrypted storage, firewalls and password protection systems to safeguard the confidentiality of Customers’ personal information. Each of our employees and agents is aware of our security policies, and your information is only available to those employees and agents who need it to perform their jobs. Although we have taken measures to keep user information secure that we think are reasonable, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable and that we cannot guarantee the security of your information. We cannot control the actions of other users with whom You share your information. We cannot guarantee that only authorized persons will view your information. We are not responsible for third-party circumvention or hacking of any privacy settings or security measures, and we hereby disclaim all liability related to such third-party action. Any transmission of your information or use of the Services is at your own risk. You can reduce these risks by using common-sense security practices such as choosing a strong password, using different passwords for websites, and using up-to-date antivirus software.

10\. NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES.

If we change this Privacy Policy and seek to use your personal information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, You will be notified via e-mail or otherwise in some manner through the Services. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect personal information already stored by us, we will post a notice on the Website notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post such a notice, we will also e-mail users who have opted to receive communications from us to notify them of the changes in our privacy practices. If we are using the personal information of any EU individual on the basis of that individual’s consent, and we change this privacy policy to permit any use or disclosure of such EU individual’s personal information that is materially different than the uses for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by such person, we or the applicable Data Controller will obtain such individual’s consent before we make such further uses of such EU individual’s personal information.

11\. EU-US AND SWISS-US PRIVACY SHIELD FRAMEWORKS.

The Company complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively.

The Company has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/.

We process user information in our facilities in the United States. All information subject to this Privacy Policy is collected in the United States, or obtained in other countries and transferred to the United States. Regardless where it originated, all user information subject to this Privacy Policy receives the same level of privacy protection as described herein.

12\. ENFORCEMENT.

In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, the Company commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy and our compliance with it and the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles should first contact us at privacy@automatedinsights.com or Automated Insights, Inc. at 512 S. Mangum Street, Suite 400, Durham, NC 27701.

We also follow internal procedures for verifying that our commitments under this Privacy Policy have been implemented, and will remedy problems arising out of a failure to comply with this Privacy Policy and the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles.

The Company is also subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC). The Company has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus.

If You do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit https://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers for more information and to file a complaint.

Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel.

For additional information, you may visit www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction.
